PhD Candidate, MSc. Albi Dode

Software Engineer & DPO

Keplerstraße 30/3, 89073 Ulm, Germany | +491638587648 | info@albidode.info

in linkedin.com/in/albidode
albidode.info

Summary

Software Engineer/Developer and Data Protection Officer providing technical support, developing software programs, web sites, giving information security/DPO consulence. I have knowledge in Agile methodology for leading teams in achieving excellence in client satisfaction, productivity, and profitability. Firm mindset with a drive to find solutions to new problems. Strong analytical skills and detailed to project's requirements. Adaption well in groups and a willingness to understand the various roles played by fellow team members. Perform tests and find ways to eliminate bugs in the programs. Build interactive and dynamic websites. Experience with remote projects during master studies. Bachelor in Computer science (State University of New York) and Master in Software Engineering (Mälardalens högskola Västerås).

PhD in "The Development of a generic framework for mobile data sensing and mobile patient intervention" (Universität Ulm).

Work experience

PhD 2019

ESIT & University of Ulm

The Development of a generic framework for mobile data sensing and mobile patient intervention

PHP Developer - BlueScreen

2019 - 2019

2018 - 2019

* Responsible for writing server-side web application logic * Develop back-end components, connect the application with other web services, and support the front-end developers by integrating their work with the application. CI/CD processes * PHP with Codelgniter.

Technical Writer - Ericsson

* Supporting documents to communicate complex and technical information * Explain complex information in a clear and concise manner and working with the staff to ensure accuracy of product functionalities. * ArborText TagTool.

Contribute to the establishment and evolution of the digital organization.

Work together with the product owner and other team in an agile environment. Investigate and suggest new technologies and solution.

Document several IT systems.

IT and DPO - qPharmetra Sweden

2018 - 2018

* Cisco for cloud management for security, networking, and application control * Inform about security risk for Microsoft products * Gather requirements and identify the costs and the time needed to implement the IT project * Supporting, monitoring and maintaining workplace technology and responding to users' requests for help. *Support for Office365 and Web technologies.

Identify and understand business needs.

Contribute to the establishment and evolution of the digital organization.

Maintain and develop/refactor existing software. Perform code reviews.

Lecturer - Albanian University Tirana

2015 - 2015

Lecturer and for one semester in Tirana and Berat for the subjects : Computer Architecture & Web Applications.

IT support - Albanian Psychologists Association

2014 - 2015

* Made a website using in HTML/PHP/MySql and a documentation content management system using Java. * SEO optimization.

 $Transform\ abstract\ problems\ into\ concrete\ road maps\ for\ new\ digital\ solutions.$

Design and develop new software.

Technical Support Specialist - Albanian Business Partner

2012 - 2014

*Meet with the client to determine customization requirements *Work with client to define the scope of the project *Clarify clients system specifications, understand their specific work practices



Skills

Methodology

Agile, Scrum

Testing

Jira, JUnit

Databases

Firebase, Oracle, MS Access, SQL, MySQL

Languages

C++, C#, VB .Net,Java, HTML/PHP/Codelgniter,JS ,Python,R

Applications

Weka, SPSS, Windows & Linux Environment, Active Directory, Exchange / Outlook , MS Office, IDEs: NetBeans, Eclipse, Visual Studio, ArborText, GitLab, Dita XML, ArborText TagTool

Experience

Different merit projects such as :

BusPlanner for Ericsson Sweden -Pvthon.HTML.JS.Firebase

Model-based plugin in Eclipse:Java

Different websites in HTML/PHP/MySql

Jira, JUnit, SPSS, Weka, R - Used for my master thesis.

Java,HTML/PHP/MySql,JS,Python,ArborText,GitLab,Cod elgniter and Microsoft Support: Used in work and university studies.

Python: Limited

 $\ensuremath{\mathsf{My}}$ bachelor thesis was written in Java for Android using Eclipse.

C++, C#, VB .Net during bachelor years

Languages

English : C 1

Italian : B2 Spanish : B1

Swedish: A1

French : Basic words

German: A2

Certification

GDPR - DPO

*Travel to customer's site *Diagnose and refine challenges & opportunities *Help clients with change-management activities *Purchase systems where appropriate *Design, test, install and monitor new systems. *Facilitated network support for hospitals in Tirana for a software written in Java. * Supported different troubleshoots within Windows systems.

Introduce and implement relevant framework and tools.

Freelancer

Different websites for private companies using HTML/PHP/MySql.

Helped several companies setting up: Office 365, Skype for Business, SharePoint, Active Directory

Education

Bachelor in Computer Science

2010 - 2014

University of New York Tirana & State University of New York

Thesis: Hotel Booking Android application

Master of Science in Software Engineering

2015 - 2017

Mälardalen University

Under Erasmus Mundus Scholarship

Thesis: Effectiveness of fault prediction

Download PDF - DIVA Portal

Thesis conducted at Accedo Broadband AB Stockholm

Contributions

 $Certification from \textit{\textit{FER University}} for high results in Distributed systems course - 2017.$

Finalist at "From Gjirokastra to Gjirokastra" competition - 2014.

Rotary Club Tirana - Charity work for families in needs in Mirdita - 2013.

Core Competencies

- Scrum/Agile
- Project Management
- Troubleshooting
- Analytical skills
- Group work
- Knowledge of intended audience

- Coding
- Technical Support
- Quality Assurance
- Research in new technologies
- Multitasking
- Adapt in teams with different cultures

Articles and publications

Technology and democratic citizenship connection in Albania- UNIEL – 2014

A.Dode, E.Dode

 $https://www.researchgate.net/profile/Albi_Dode/publication/314235740_Technology_and_democratic_citizenship_connection_in_Albania/links/58bc3f22a6fdcc2d14e58f21/Technology_and_democratic_citizenship_connection_in_Albania/links/58bc3f22a6fdcc2d14e58f21/Technology_and_democratic_citizenship_connection_in_Albania/links/58bc3f22a6fdcc2d14e58f21/Technology_and_democratic_citizenship_connection_in_Albania/links/58bc3f22a6fdcc2d14e58f21/Technology_and_democratic_citizenship_connection_in_Albania/links/58bc3f22a6fdcc2d14e58f21/Technology_and_democratic_citizenship_connection_in_Albania/links/58bc3f22a6fdcc2d14e58f21/Technology_and_democratic_citizenship_connection_in_Albania/links/58bc3f22a6fdcc2d14e58f21/Technology_and_democratic_citizenship_connection_in_Albania/links/58bc3f22a6fdcc2d14e58f21/Technology_and_democratic_citizenship_connection_in_Albania/links/58bc3f22a6fdcc2d14e58f21/Technology_and_democratic_citizenship_connection_in_Albania/links/58bc3f22a6fdcc2d14e58f21/Technology_and_democratic_citizenship_connection_in_Albania/links/58bc3f22a6fdcc2d14e58f21/Technology_and_democratic_citizenship_connection_in_Albania/links/58bc3f22a6fdcc2d14e58f21/Technology_and_democratic_citizenship_connection_in_Albania/links/58bc3f22a6fdcc2d14e58f21/Technology_and_democratic_citizenship_connection_in_Albania/links/58bc3f22a6fdcc2d14e58f21/Technology_and_democratic_citizenship_connection_in_Albania/links/58bc3f22a6fdcc2d14e58f21/Technology_and_democratic_citizenship_connection_in_Albania/links/58bc3f22a6fdcc2d14e58f21/Technology_and_democratic_citizenship_connection_in_Albania/links/58bc3f22a6fdcc2d14e58f21/Technology_and_democratic_citizenship_connection_in_Albania/links/58bc3f22a6fdcc2d14e58f21/Technology_and_democratic_citizenship_connection_in_Albania/links/58bc3f22a6fdcc2d14e58f21/Technology_and_democratic_citizenship_citizenship_citizenship_citizenship_citizenship_citizenship_citizenship_citizenship_citizenship_citizenship_citizenship_citizenship_citizenship_citizenship_citizenship_citizenship_citizenship_citizenship_citi$

The Values of Civic Education through Information Technology- Albanian University – 2015

http://www.mcser.org/journal/index.php/ajis/article/view/7397

https://doi.org/10.5901/ajis.2015.v4n2s2p15

A.Dode, E.Dode

Teenagers Problems Related with Social-Networking - Epoka University - 2015

A Dode, G Rexha, L Nishani

Proceedings of the 5th International Conference on European Studies 5th ICES

http://dspace.epoka.edu.al/handle/1/1316

An Android-based Application for Mining Customer Satisfaction

International Scientific Conference COMPUTER SCIENCE'2015

08-10 September 2015, Durrës, Albania

Albi Dode, Erind Bedalli

http://cs.tu-sofia.bg/conf/ComputerScience15_Program.pdf

NETWORK SECURITY THROUGH VULNERABILITY ANALYSIS

Albi Dode, Silvester Hasani

http://www.inderscience.com/jhome.php?jcode=ijkms

Effectiveness of fault prediction - Review - Albanian University - 2016

Albi Dode, Genta Rexha, Kinan Dindan

http://www.albanianuniversity.al/al/njoftime/401-konferenca-nderkombetare-dhjetor-2016

Assessment of an IT network security with information gathering tools - Albanian University 2015

Albi Dode, Silvester Hasani

 $https://www.researchgate.net/publication/314235536_Assessment_of_an_IT_network_security_with_information_gathering_tools$

Page Rank Algorithm

Albi Dode, Silvester Hasani

http://www.iosrjournals.org/iosr-jce/pages/19(1)Version-3.html

https://doi.org/10.9790/0661-1901030107

 $http://www.researcherid.com/ProfileView.action?returnCode=ROUTER.Unauthorized\&queryString=KG0UuZjN5Wlte3fin7unE58Fn9h7A31B3YOFDl0O78c%253D\&SrcApp=CR\&Init=Yes http://journals.indexcopernicus.com/issue.php?id=11660\&id_issue=886308$

Why do programmers prefer Opencl for Gpu programming? - European University 2016

Albi Dode, Genta Rexha

https://www.academia.edu/36823300/Why_do_programmers_prefer_Opencl_for_Gpu_programming

The challenges of implementing General Data Protection Law (GDPR)

Albi Dode

 $https://www.researchgate.net/publication/327829348_The_challenges_of_implementing_General_Data_Protection_Law_GD_PR$

Smartphone Apps in the Context of Tinnitus: Systematic Review

Muntazir Mehdi, Constanze Riha, Patrick Neff, Albi Dode, Rüdiger Pryss, Winfried Schlee, Manfred Reichert, Franz J Hauck https://www.mdpi.com/1424-8220/20/6/1725/htm

Conferences

British Tinnitus Association Conference - London September 2019

R Workshop - Sietges, Spain October 2019